Murali Selvaraj

System Engineer

I have 5 years of work experience, with 2 years as a Full Stack Web Developer with MERN stack expertise and 3 years as a SAP Security Consultant. My goal is to use my skills to build high-quality websites and learn new technologies while staying up-to-date with industry best practices. I'm seeking a position in web development that allows me to continue developing my career and contribute to the company's growth.



- muraliselvaraj.18@gmail.com
- Tiruchirappalli, India
- in linkedin.com/in/murali-selvaraj

- 8526682169
- muraliselvaraj-portfolio.netlify.app/
- github.com/Murali07

WORK EXPERIENCE

MERN Stack Developer Tata Consultancy Services

08/2021 - Present

Chennai

Responsibilities

- Developed multiple POCs to create a user interface in React JS.
- Responsible for making responsive web pages using Bootstrap and Media Queries.
- Hands on experience in developing Single Page Applications (SPA) using React JS and Node.js.
- Used Object Oriented Programming concepts to develop UI components that could be reused across the Web Application.
- Hands on experience in developing Food Web Application using React JS, Bootstrap, Node. JS, Express and MongoDB.
- Implemented generating the verification hash code using Node JS and added user validation by using Node JS, Mongoose.

SAP Security Consultant

Tata Consultancy Services

06/2018 - 07/2021 Responsibilities Mumbai

- Worked on user administration using SU01, SU10 to perform various user set up related activities like new user creation/modifications, lock/unlock, deletion, password reset and extending expired users.
- Creating and modifying Single, Derived and Composite Roles using Profile Generator.
- Handled troubleshooting authorization issues using the SAP transactions like SU53, ST01, STAUTHTRACE.
- Good experience with Physical Inventory and Role Review process. Solved functional and technical obstacles and worked closely with project team from different streams.
- Delivered SAP training, user support and knowledge transfer at end of project and followed up to verify successful implementation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering

Bannari Amman Institute of Technology

07/2014 - 04/2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: React, Node.js, Express, Spring, Spring Boot

Database: MongoDB, SQL, MySQL

Version Control: Git

Cloud Services: AWS

Containerization: Docker

Other Tools: Postman, VS Code, Netlify, Render

ACHIEVEMENTS

Special Recognition Award for contributions to the Canadian Rollout project.

Certificate of appreciation for contribution in Siemens Healthineers

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Zen Desk (06/2022 - 07/2022)

- Zen Desk is a web application for residential/apartments query raising app.
- Technologies used: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, ReactBootstrap.
- Click <u>here</u> to check this project.

Food Delivery App (08/2022 - 09/2022)

- A minimum viable product for a food delivery web application.
- Technologies used: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, ReactBootstrap, JWT.
- Click here to check this project.

CERTIFICATES

Zen Class Full Stack Developer Program (01/2022 - 06/2022) ♂

GUVI Geek Networks, IITM Research Park

LANGUAGES

English
Full Professional Proficiency

Tamil

Native or Bilingual Proficiency